

JAVIER MORALES

IT SYSTEMS ENGINEER

CONTACT

+353838848742
MORALESJMORENO@GMAIL.COM
LINKEDIN.COM/IN/JAVIERMORALESM/

PROFILE

Dedicated Senior Cloud Engineer, experienced in several fields of computer science such as DB's, Virtualization, Storage, Networking as well as an abroad exposure to support multiplatform international environments.

Over the past few years, I've been focused on Cloud and Virtual environments as an Administrator/System Engineer, for big IT Enterprises and customer-oriented services. Complemented with a strong foundation of knowledge around VMware and AWS cloud services and the cloud ecosystems (Software Define DC).

EXPERIENCE

SENIOR SYSTEM ADMINISTRATOR & CLOUD ENGINEER

ESENTIRE LTD. (IRELAND) | NOV 2018 - PRESENT

- Creating and utilizing tools to monitor our applications and services in the cloud including system health indicators, trend identification, and anomaly detection (NOC)
- Planning, designing and developing cloud-based applications and services (laaS, PaaS, SaaS)
- Developed experience with Cloud-based hosting solutions (AWS-EC2/S3, VMware, VRops)
- Provide High-Level system management solutions

TECHNICAL SUPPORT ENGINEER LEVEL 2

VMWARE (IRELAND) | SEP 2016 - NOV 2018

- Manage and support vSphere and Vrops incidents, multiplatform technical assistance, Network L2/L3 and Storage troubleshooting
- Proactively provide guidance following best practices

IT SYSTEMS & OPS ENGINEER

HAVAS MEDIA (SPAIN) | MAY 2015 - AUG 2016

- Managing cloud environments in accordance with company security guidelines.
- VMware Administrator (P2V Migration deploy, configure and manage virtual infrastructure)
- Hands-on experience on Amazon Web Services AWS (S3, EC2, VPC, CloudWatch)

VMWARE ENGINEER

WINCOR NIXDORF (SPAIN) | MAY 2014 - MAY 2015

- Stealthily plan and lead the deployment of the cloud solution
- VMware SME Subject Matter expert
- Designing and implementing new Virtual Environments (server-less integrated VMware)

2ND LINE IT ENGINEER

ROCHE PHARMACEUTICAL (SPAIN) | NOV 2013 - MAY 2014

- Strategize daily monitoring, management, troubleshooting and issue resolution to systems and services hosted on cloud resources
- Supporting VMware, Networking, and Backup management, Storage Systems, Blade Servers, SAN, Backup infrastructure

HELPDESK LEVEL 1-2 IT ENGINEER

VODAFONE (SPAIN) | DEC 2010 - NOV 2013

- Advance application support for internal company employees
- Using ticketing tools such as Spider, Remedy and HP Service Manager



JAVIER MORALES

IT SYSTEMS ENGINEER

EDUCATION

MASTER DIPLOMA IN CYBER SECURITY (MSC LEVEL 9) UNIVERSIDAD DE LA RIOJA UNIR, SPAIN 2020-2021

HIGHER DIPLOMA WITH HONORS IN CLOUD COMPUTER SCIENCE

NATIONAL COLLEGE OF IRELAND, IRELAND | 2017-2019

TECHNICAL HIGHER DIPLOMA IN MULTIPLATFORM APPS DEVELOPMENT

I.E.S. I.E.S EL RINCÓN, SPAIN | 2011-2013

TECHNICAL HIGHER DIPLOMA IN TELECOMMUNICATIONS AND INFORMATION SYSTEMS

I.E.S. POLITÉCNICO, SPAIN | 2003-2005

LANGUAGES SPOKEN

SPANISH, ENGLISH

SKILLS

- Software Define DataCenter Veeam Backup & Disaster SDDC
- Linux (Centos, Redhat, Debian)
- DB (SQL, PSQL, MariaDB)
- Networking (NOC)
- Amazon AWS (IAM, EC2, S3, Migration Projects (On-CloudWatch, VPC)
- Technical Documentation
- CI/CD Secure Software Dev scripting Life Cycle (SDDLC)

- Recovery
- VMware Design, Deployment and Implementation
- Monitoring (Nagios, Solarwinds, Service Now)
- Premise to Cloud)
- Python and Bash Automation

COURSES & SEMINARS

- AWS Solutions Architect Associate, JMG
- PMP, IPMA
- Android Apps Creation & Development, UNED
- Hack the box, TryHackme Hands-on labs
- Udemy, INE, O'Reilly, AWS self-paced active courses

CERTIFICATIONS

- VCP550 VCP5-DCV
- 2V0-621D VCP6-DCV
- 3V0-623 VCAP 6 DATA CENTER VIRTUALIZATION DEPLOYMENT
- 2V0-642 VCP6-NV (NSX V6.2)
 AWS SYSOPS ASSOCIATED
- PMP BY IPMA
- COMPTIA LINUX+
- LPIC-1: SYSTEM **ADMNINSTRATOR**
- AWS SOLUTION ARCHITECT **ASSOCIATED**